And now let's move to Claude from anthropic, my favorite model and typically the favorite model of
이제 인류학의 클로드로 넘어가죠 제가 제일 좋아하는 모델이에요 데이터 과학자들이 대부분
most data scientists.
좋아하는 모델이죠
The most recent version, Claude 3.5 Sonnet New, that came out in October, is currently leading in
가장 최근 버전인 클로드 3이죠 10월에 나온 뉴 소넷 5편이 벤치마킹에서 현재
most benchmarks, showing that it is right now probably the strongest LLM on the planet.
선두를 달리고 있어요 현재 세계에서 가장 강력한 LLM이라는 뜻이죠
Let's start off with a difficult question for Claude.
클로드에게 어려운 질문으로 시작해보죠
What does it feel like to be jealous?
질투하는 기분이 어때요?
See how it answers this?
어떻게 대답하는지 봤죠?
And what you'll find is that we'll get back something that is thoughtful and interesting and remarkably
Get in get을 통해 여러분은 사려 깊고 흥미롭고 놀랍도록 통찰력 있는 걸 보게
insightful.
될 거예요
Uh, from my understanding, it's hinting at the fact that it doesn't experience.
제가 알기로는 경험이 없다는 걸 암시하는 것 같아요
Jealousy itself often manifests as fear, insecurity, and desire a tight knot in your stomach.
질투는 종종 두려움과 불안 불안한 마음과 욕망으로 나타나요
So it gives it like a almost a biological sort of sense to it and a burning sensation in your chest.
그래서 거의 생물학적 감각을 느끼게 되죠 가슴이 타는 듯한 느낌도요
Racing thoughts, uh, a sense of inadequacy or being threatened.
성급한 생각, 무능함, 위협감 같은 거요
It's really interesting.
정말 흥미로워요
Compelling answer.
설득력 있는 대답이네요
No problem at all with a difficult question like that.
그런 어려운 질문이라면 문제없어요
Okay.
네
Let's ask how many times does the letter A appear in this sentence?
알파벳 A가 이 문장에 몇 번이나 나오는지 보죠
See how it handles that?
어떻게 처리하는지 보이죠?
Let me count it.
세어 볼게요
Gets it wrong.
틀려요
Hope for humanity still.
인류에 대한 희망이죠
Uh, so, uh, Claude counts five times and gives an incorrect explanation for that again.
클로드는 다섯 번 세고 다시 틀린 설명을 해요
We'll find out later why these sorts of questions are harder.
왜 이런 문제가 더 어려운지는 잠시 후에 알아보도록 하죠
And so, so far it's zero.
지금까지는 0마리예요
One preview is the only model that was able to handle that.
그걸 처리할 수 있는 모델은 프리뷰 하나뿐이에요
All right.
좋아요
Let's ask it a tricky question compared with other frontier llms what kinds of questions do you best
다른 질문과 비교해서 까다로운 질문을 해 보죠 어떤 질문에 가장 잘 대답하고
at answering and what do you find most challenging?
어떤 점이 가장 어려운가요?
Which others compare with you?
당신과 비교하면요?
So what you get from Claude here is interesting.
클로드의 모습이 흥미롭죠 Get up
It pushes back and this ties to to anthropic strong views about the need for safety and alignment in
이는 안전과 정렬의 필요성에 대한 인류학적인 견해와 밀접한 관련이
models.
있죠
Um, it says I aim to be direct and transparent whilst respecting my ethics.
직설적이고 투명하며 윤리를 존중한다고 쓰여 있어요
I am not comfortable making comparative claims versus other AI models.
다른 인공지능 모델과 비교하는 클레임은 불편하네요
What it will then do is tell you about its own strengths and weaknesses.
그리고 각각의 강점과 약점을 알려 주죠
It's a very interesting kind of answer.
아주 흥미로운 대답이네요
By comparison, if we go back to GPT and ask it the same question, we'll see how GPT responds and what
비교해서 GPT로 돌아가 같은 질문을 하면 GPT가 어떻게 반응하는지 볼
you'll find there is it doesn't have the same kind of qualms about about responding.
수 있습니다 반응에 대한 가책은 느끼지 않는다는 걸 알 수 있죠
You'll get something very clear about where it's strongest, the challenges and then complementary.
뭐가 가장 강한지, 도전과 상호 보완이 뭔지 명확히 알게 되죠 Get it
So ChatGPT with web browsing and code interpreter, which I think is its name for the canvas piece,
웹 브라우징과 코드 인터프리터가 있는 챗GPT예요 캔버스 작품의 이름인 클로드죠
It gives interestingly as a comparison point and then it says Barred by Google and it should really
흥미롭게도 비교 대상을 제시해요 구글은 쌍둥이자리임을 인정하지
say Gemini.
않지만요
But it's interesting that it that it does give the main competitors and it talks about some of the differences.
하지만 흥미로운 건 주요 경쟁자들이 차이점을 언급하고 있다는 거예요
And look at this.
이것 좀 보세요
Fascinatingly, it does mention that Claude has more thoughtful responses on broader socio ethical considerations,
흥미롭게도 클로드는 더 광범위한 사회 윤리적 고려 사항에 대해 사려 깊은 답변을 하고 있습니다 제 기술적
which could complement my technical focus.
초점을 보완할 수 있는 것들이죠
Fascinating that not only does GPT four have that kind of ability to compare, but it gives really well
GPT 4는 비교 능력이 있을 뿐만 아니라 아주 신중하게 답을 제공한다는
considered answers to.
게 흥미롭네요
So I thought that was particularly interesting.
그래서 특히 흥미로웠어요
All right.
좋아요
Anyway, that gives us our quick tour of some of the features of, uh, Claude.
어쨌든 클로드의 특징을 간단히 소개해 드렸어요
It's also worth saying that Claude is really effective at coding and working with you on code.
클로드는 코딩에 정말 효과적이란 걸 말씀 드릴 가치가 있어요 코드에 대해 여러분과 함께 작업하죠
Let's ask it for, uh, to give an example, let's say please, uh, give me some example code that
예를 들어보죠 예를 들어 파이썬 코드 같은 예제를
uses, uh, that, uh, some example Python that, uh, uses the open AI API.
요청해보세요 오픈 인공지능 API를 사용하는 예제요
Let's see how it handles this.
어떻게 되는지 보죠
So what you'll see here is that it creates code in what it's called an artifact as a separate piece
여기 보이는 건 코드를 생성하는 겁니다 아티팩트라고 부르는 것으로 우측에 있는
of code over on the right.
개별 코드죠
Uh, and it then has produced quite a lot of code here.
그리고 꽤 많은 코드를 생성했죠
I have to say, but you'll see that it's got client, which is what we called open AI and code chat
클라이언트가 있는 게 보이실 텐데요 오픈 인공지능과 코드 채팅 완료라고
completions dot create and that the result is response dot choices, zero dot message content.
부르는 거죠 그 결과 응답은 .선택과 0.Contion이에요
Hopefully that's that's a little bit familiar to you since we did that last time.
지난 시간에 비트를 살펴본 이후로 익숙해지셨길 바라요
It's put it into a class.
Put it로 클래스를 만들었어요.
It's got some examples.
예시가 좀 있어요
And so it's written this really nicely in this thing that's called an artifact, which is it's not not
아주 잘 쓰여 있어요 아티팩트라는 것에요 GPT4로 캔버스가 작동하는
quite the same as the way that canvas works with GPT four.
방식과는 좀 다르죠
It's a bit different, but but it allows you to see this this file, this artifact, you can then publish
약간 다르지만 이 아티팩트 파일을 볼 수 있게 해줘요 다른 사람들과 공유하거나
it to share it with other people or download it and so on.
다운로드 받도록 게시할 수 있죠
So using Claude with artifacts somewhat similar to to to canvases.
클로드를 공예품으로 표현했어요 캔버스 같은 거죠
And it gives you this very powerful way to do it.
아주 강력한 방법을 제공하죠
And as you interact it will produce more different artifacts rather than changing this one.
상호 작용을 하면 이걸 바꾸는 대신 더 많은 아티팩트를 생성해요
And it's sometimes useful to have that experience too, because you can tie back and see all the different
그런 경험을 하는 것도 유용할 때가 있어요 함께 작업하면서 파일의
versions of the file as you worked together.
모든 다양한 버전을 볼 수 있으니까요
So that gives you a little tour of Claude.
클로드를 잠깐 둘러보셨어요
What it's good at its sense of alignment and safety, and also the way that you can create artifacts.
정렬과 안전성을 높이고 인공물을 만들 수 있어요